So this is a good time for a quick recap of the last couple of lessons.
このへんで これまでのレッスンを 簡単に まとめてみましょう
Here we have two models.
ここに 2つの モデルがあります
The bad model on the left and the good model on the right.
左は 良くないモデル 右は 良いモデルです
And for each one of those we calculate the cross entropy which is the sum of
どちらに対しても クロスエントロピーを 求めるため
the negatives of the logarithms off the probabilities of the points being their colors.
各点が その色になる確率の 負の対数を 合計します
And we conclude that the one on the right is better
その結果 右のモデルの方が 良いことが わかります
because a cross entropy is much smaller.
クロスエントロピーが ずっと小さいためです
So let's actually calculate the formula for the error function.
では 誤差関数の式を 実際に 計算してみましょう
Let's split into two cases.
2つのケースに 分けます
The first case being when y=1.
最初のケースは y=1の 場合です
So when the point is blue to begin with,
つまり青の点です
the model tells us that the probability of being blue is the prediction y_hat.
このモデルで 青である確率は ŷです
So for these two points the probabilities are 0.6 and 0.2.
そこで この2つの点の 確率は 0.6と 0.2です
As we can see the point in the blue area has
ご覧のとおり 青い領域にある点は
more probability of being blue than the point in the red area.
青である確率が 赤い領域の点より 高くなります
And our error is simply the negative logarithm of this probability.
誤差は この確率の 負の対数です
So it's precisely minus logarithm of y_hat.
正確にいうと ŷの負の対数です
In the figure it's minus logarithm of 0.6. and minus logarithm of 0.2.
図では 0.6の 負の対数と 0.2の 負の対数に なります
Now if y=0, so when the point is red,
さて y=0の場合 つまり赤の点については
then we need to calculate the probability of the point being red.
点が赤である確率を 計算する必要があります
The probability of the point being red is one minus the probability of the point being
点が赤である確率は 1から 青である確率を 引いた値
blue which is precisely 1 minus the prediction y_hat.
つまり 1-ŷです
So the error is precisely the negative logarithm of
そこで 誤差は この確率の 負の対数
this probability which is negative logarithm of 1 - y_hat.
つまり 1-ŷの 負の対数です
In this case we get negative logarithm 0.1 and negative logarithm 0.7.
この例では 0.1の 負の対数と 0.7 の負の対数 となります
So we conclude that the error is a negative logarithm of y_hat if the point is blue.
そのため 誤差は 青の点の場合は yの 負の対数です
And negative logarithm of one - y_hat the point is red.
赤の点の場合は 1-ŷの 負の対数です
We can summarize these two formulas into this one.
この 2つの式を 1つにまとめましょう
Error = - (1-y)(ln( 1- y_hat)) - y ln(y_hat).
誤差 = - (1-y)(ln( 1- ŷ)) - y ln(ŷ)
Why does this formula work?
どうして この式で 計算できるのでしょうか
Well because if the point is blue,
点が青なら y=1なので
then y=1 which means 1-y=0 which makes the first term
1-y=0となり 最初の項が 0になります
0 and the second term is simply logarithm of y_hat.
2つ目の項は 単に ŷの対数です
Similarly, if the point is red then y=0.
同様に 点が赤なら y=0です
So the second term of the formula is 0 and the first one is logarithm of 1- y_hat.
そのため 2つ目の項が 0 となり 最初の項は 1-ŷです
Now the formula for the error function is simply the sum over
誤差関数の 計算式は 点の 誤差関数の
all the error functions of points which is precisely the summation here.
総和であり このようになります
That's going to be this 4.8 we have over here.
これが 左側と等しい 4.8になります
Now by convention we'll actually consider the average,
慣例では 和ではなく
not the sum which is where we are dividing by n over here.
平均を取るので nで 割ります
This will turn the 4.8 into a 1.2.
これで 4.8が 1.2に なります
From now on we'll use this formula as our error function.
今後は この式を 誤差関数として 使用します
And now since y_hat is given by the sigmoid of the linear function wx + b,
さて ŷは 線形関数wx+bの シグモイド関数であることから
then the total formula for the error is actually in terms
誤差の計算式は
of w and b which are the weights of the model.
モデルの重みである wと bで 表せます
And it's simply the summation we see here.
このような 式になります
In this case y_i is just the label of the point x_superscript_i.
この例で y_iは 点xの ラベルに 添え字i を加えたものです
So now that we've calculated it our goal is to minimize it.
誤差関数を 求めましたが 目標は その最小化です
And that's what we'll do next.
次の ステップで それを実行します
And just a small aside,
これは 余談ですが
what we did is for binary classification problems.
ここで解いたのは 2項分類問題です
If we have a multiclass classification problem then
多クラス分類問題の 場合は
the error is now given by the multiclass entropy.
誤差は 多クラスエントロピーとなります
This formula is given here where for every data point we take the product
式は このようになり 各データ点に対して
of the label times the logarithm of the prediction and then we average all these values.
ラベルと 予測の対数の 積を求め すべての値の 平均を計算します
And again it's a nice exercise to convince yourself that
クラスが 2つの場合は どちらの式も 同じ結果になるので
the two are the same when there are just two classes.
ぜひ 自分で 試してみてください